<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>home on Mátyás Budavári</title>
    <link>https://budavariam.github.io/featured/home/</link>
    <description>Recent content in home on Mátyás Budavári</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://budavariam.github.io/featured/home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Starschema Hackathon 2021</title>
      <link>https://budavariam.github.io/posts/2021/12/12/starschema-hackathon-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budavariam.github.io/posts/2021/12/12/starschema-hackathon-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Hungary, around the end of the year, we usually have some mandatory transferred workdays,
when we have to work on Saturdays instead of the days around holidays.
It&amp;rsquo;s not unusual for companies to let their workers spend their time in a more fun way,
that&amp;rsquo;s what we did with an optional hackathon.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSSQL Server Basics</title>
      <link>https://budavariam.github.io/posts/2021/09/29/mssql-server-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budavariam.github.io/posts/2021/09/29/mssql-server-basics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the past couple of weeks I&amp;rsquo;ve started to work with Microsoft SQL Server.
I have a pretty good founation of SQL from high school, but I&amp;rsquo;ve only used PostgreSQL so far in my carreer.
I collect the snippets I found to be the most useful ones that helped me getting started.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plotly Dash Development Tips</title>
      <link>https://budavariam.github.io/posts/2021/04/05/plotly-dash-development-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budavariam.github.io/posts/2021/04/05/plotly-dash-development-tips/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last year I was working on some dash-plotly applications/dashboards.
It was confusing at first, I learned a lot during that time, I&amp;rsquo;d like to share my gathered experience.
The docs already contain useful information, I do not wish to repeat them.
There are many example pages in github, my goal is to collect my most visited pages here,
so it&amp;rsquo;ll be easier to start out with development.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vim</title>
      <link>https://budavariam.github.io/posts/2021/03/13/vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budavariam.github.io/posts/2021/03/13/vim/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My first memory with vim is in early 2010s, I was just learning git, and I messed up my repo badly,
a colleague came to help, he told me seemingly random sequence of characters to type,
and suddenly everything went back to normal. Git&amp;rsquo;s default editor was vim and I think we did an interactive rebase.
We might have just fixed it in an other way, but still it felt powerful.
Later on I saw vim books at the operators&amp;rsquo; desks, and I got really curious of what it is and how can it help my daily work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Think Outside The Box</title>
      <link>https://budavariam.github.io/posts/2021/02/27/think-outside-the-box/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budavariam.github.io/posts/2021/02/27/think-outside-the-box/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the past few days I&amp;rsquo;ve been working in manual mode on multiple linux boxes simultaneously.
I have to follow logs, modify configurations and kill/start applications all at once.
I got confused pretty fast of what server am I connected to in a certain console pane, and where are my operations.
On top of that my ISP had a huge traffic hit these days, and my VPN connection dropped constantly.
I dusted off my knowledge about some tools that boosted my productivity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clipboard Goodies For Productivity</title>
      <link>https://budavariam.github.io/posts/2021/01/20/clipboard-goodies-for-productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budavariam.github.io/posts/2021/01/20/clipboard-goodies-for-productivity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever typed ctrl-c instead of ctrl-v and had to recopy again?
Have you ever needed to copy and paste multiple entries at once from a page causing you to switch back and forth?
Have you ever needed to copy the output of a program running in the terminal?
I did, and got fed up with them almost 5 years ago, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how you can eliminate these problems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things I Wish I Had Known As a Junior</title>
      <link>https://budavariam.github.io/posts/2020/09/19/things-i-wish-i-had-known-as-a-junior/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budavariam.github.io/posts/2020/09/19/things-i-wish-i-had-known-as-a-junior/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few days ago I read a question in twitter, what is the thing that you wish you had known when you started to code.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supercharge your command line</title>
      <link>https://budavariam.github.io/posts/2020/04/27/supercharge-your-command-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budavariam.github.io/posts/2020/04/27/supercharge-your-command-line/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The commmand line can be your best friend during development, if you take some time to get to know its capabilities.
But even if you know what it can help you with, you can still extend it.
I&amp;rsquo;d like to introduce you some of my favourite tools, &lt;code&gt;fzf&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;oh-my-zsh&lt;/code&gt;.
By the end of this post I hope you&amp;rsquo;ll see how well they can work together with you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
